$TB_TradeAndBarter	Trade & Barter
$TB_BarterRates	Barter Rates
$TB_PlayerVariables	Player Variables
$TB_MerchantVariables	Merchant Variables
$TB_MerchantInventory	Merchant Inventory
$TB_Presets	Presets
$TB_BarterPresets	Barter Presets
$TB_ModifyBarterSettings	Modify Barter Settings
$TB_Settings	Settings
$TB_RespawnSettings	Respawn Settings
$TB_GlobalPriceAdjustments	Global Price Adjustments
$TB_BuyingPrices	Buying Prices
$TB_SellingPrices	Selling Prices
$TB_StartMod	Start Mod
$TB_StopMod	Stop Mod
$TB_%BetterPrices	{0}% better prices
$TB_%Prices	{0}% prices
$TB_%Higher	{0}% higher
$TB_Gold	{0} gold
$TB_Status	Status
$TB_Thane	Thane
$TB_FactionMember	Faction Member
$TB_FactionLeader	Faction Leader
$TB_Relationship	Relationship
$TB_Friend	Friend
$TB_Ally	Ally
$TB_Lover	Lover
$TB_RaceRelations	Race Relations
$TB_UseDefaultRaceRelations	Use Default Race Relations
$TB_SetCustomRaceRelations	Set Custom Race Relations
$TB_Altmers	Altmers:
$TB_Argonians	Argonians:
$TB_Bosmers	Bosmers:
$TB_Bretons	Bretons:
$TB_Dunmers	Dunmers:
$TB_Imperials	Imperials:
$TB_Khajiits	Khajiits:
$TB_Nords	Nords:
$TB_NordStormcloaks	Nord Stormcloaks:
$TB_Orcs	Orcs:
$TB_Redguards	Redguards:
$TB_MiscFactors	Misc Factors
$TB_MerchantType	Merchant Type
$TB_JobProducers	Producers
$TB_JobInns	Innkeepers
$TB_JobSpecialists	Crafters
$TB_JobSpells	Spell Merchants
$TB_JobGeneralMerchant	General Goods
$TB_JobFence	Fence
$TB_Knowledge	Knowledge
$TB_KnowledgeableTrader	Knowledgeable Trader
$TB_OrcFriend	Blood-Kin of the Orcs
$TB_Vampire	Vampire
$TB_Naked	Naked
$TB_WearingHelmet	Wearing Helmet
$TB_WeaponDrawn	Weapon Drawn
$TB_Location	Location
$TB_EnableLocationVariables	Enable Location Price Variables
$TB_Solitude	Solitude
$TB_Markarth	Markarth
$TB_Windhelm	Windhelm
$TB_Riften	Riften
$TB_Whiterun	Whiterun
$TB_Solstheim	Solstheim
$TB_RavenRock	Raven Rock
$TB_BuyingPrices:	Buying prices:
$TB_SellingPrices:	Selling prices:
$TB_VariableMerchantGold	Variable Merchant Gold
$TB_LowVariability	Low Variability
$TB_MediumVariability	Medium Variability
$TB_HighVariability	High Variability
$TB_MerchantGold	Merchant Gold
$TB_AddRandomGold	Add Random Gold
$TB_Apothecaries	Apothecaries:
$TB_CityBlacksmiths	City Blacksmiths:
$TB_TownBlacksmiths	Town Blacksmiths:
$TB_OrcBlacksmiths	Orc Blacksmiths:
$TB_SpellMerchants	Spell Merchants:
$TB_MiscMerchants	Misc Merchants:
$TB_Innkeepers	Innkeepers:
$TB_StreetVendors	Market Vendors:
$TB_Caravans	Caravans:
$TB_FenceBase	Fence, base:
$TB_FenceStage1	Fence, stage 1:
$TB_FenceStage2	Fence, stage 2:
$TB_FenceStage3	Fence, stage 3:
$TB_FenceStage4	Fence, stage 4:
$TB_DremoraGold	Dremora Merchant:
$TB_DisableMerchantGoldOptions	Disable Merchant Gold Options
$TB_UseCustomRespawnSettings	Use Custom Respawn Settings
$TB_MerchantInventoryRespawnsin	Merchant Inventory Respawns in
$TB_Days	{0} days
$TB_Perks	Perks
$TB_CosttoInvest	Cost to Invest
$TB_IncreasedGoldAfterInvestment	Increased Gold After Investment
$TB_InventoryChangeswhenInvested	Inventory Changes when Invested
$TB_MasterTrader	Master Trader
$TB_ActivatingMod	Activating Mod
$TB_DeactivatingMod	Deactivating Mod
$TB_ClearingLists	Clearing Lists
$TB_Vanilla	None/Vanilla
$TB_Easy	Easy
$TB_Medium	Medium
$TB_Difficult	Difficult
$TB_Hardcore	Hardcore
$TB_Custom	Custom
$TB_SaveCurrentValues	Save Current Values
$TB_SavingValues	Saving
$TB_DescPresetRates	Choose from pre-defined barter settings and global adjustments. Presets can be further customized after selecting.
$TB_DescSavePreset	Save the current barter settings and global adjustments to the "Custom" preset.\nThis will overwrite any existing values saved to that preset.
$TB_DescThane	Buying and selling prices are better in cities where you are Thane.\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescFaction	Buying and selling prices are better when trading with a member of the same faction.\nIncluded factions: Thieves Guild, Dark Brotherhood, Companions, College of Winterhold, Imperials, Stormcloaks, Dawnguard, and Volkihar vampires.\nDefault: 10%
$TB_DescFactionLead	Buying and selling prices are better if you are the leader of the faction.\nThis value will stack with any Faction Member bonus.\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescFriend	Buying and selling prices are better when dealing with friends and confidants\n(affects any NPC whose relationship rank with the player is 1 or 2).\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescAlly	Buying and selling prices are better when dealing with allies\n(affects any NPC whose relationship rank with the player is 3).\nDefault: 10%
$TB_DescLover	Buying and selling prices are better when dealing with your spouse or lover\n(affects any NPC whose relationship rank with the player is 4).\nDefault: 30%
$TB_DescLocation	Enable options for different price variables based on your location.
$TB_DescSolitudeBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher in Solitude.\nDefault: 35%
$TB_DescSolitudeSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell in Solitude.\nDefault: 10%
$TB_DescMarkarthBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher in Markarth.\nDefault: 30%
$TB_DescMarkarthSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell in Markarth.\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescWindhelmBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher in Windhelm.\nDefault: 25%
$TB_DescWindhelmSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell in Windhelm.\nDefault: 10%
$TB_DescRiftenBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher in Riften.\nDefault: 20%
$TB_DescRiftenSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell in Riften.\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescWhiterunBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher in Whiterun.\nDefault: 15%
$TB_DescWhiterunSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell in Whiterun.\nDefault: 0%
$TB_DescSolstheimBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher all across Solstheim.\nDefault: 25%
$TB_DescSolstheimSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell on Solstheim.\nDefault: 0%
$TB_DescRavenRockBuy	Prices for the items you purchase are higher in Raven Rock.\nThis setting stacks with the location modifiers for Solstheim.\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescRavenRockSell	You can get higher prices for the items you sell in Raven Rock.\nThis setting stacks with the location modifiers for Solstheim.\nDefault: 5%
$TB_DescBarterMin	Increasing this number will raise the purchase price for items while decreasing the amount you get for selling them.\nDefault Requiem: 3.0
$TB_DescBarterMax	Increasing this number will raise the purchase price for items while decreasing the amount you get for selling them.\nDefault Requiem: 4.0
$TB_DescBuyBuff	Percentage adjustment to the purchase price for all items.
$TB_DescSellBuff	Percentage adjustment to the selling price for all items.
$TB_DescUseBarterRates	Allow Trade & Barter to modify the game's barter settings.\nIf you disable this option after changing the barter settings, you will need to save and quit the game.  The values will be reset upon reloading your game.
$TB_DescRaceDefault	Prices will be influenced by the racial bias the merchant feels toward the player's race.\nFriendships and individual relationships with merchants will override and cancel out any racial bias.
$TB_DescRaceCustom	Customize the degree of racial bias that merchants feel toward your character.\nThese settings can be used for custom player-races.
$TB_DescInsider	Get better prices when you know your product. Blacksmiths, fletchers, apothecaries, and spell merchants will recognize your associated skill (smithing, marksmanship, alchemy, or enchanting).\nPrices are 1% better per every 10 skill levels, max 10% better prices at 100 skill.
$TB_DescOrcFriend	Being named Blood-Kin of the Orcs will affect prices when trading with the Orc strongholds.
$TB_DescHelmet	Hiding your face behind a hood or helmet will affect prices.
$TB_DescVampire	Being a vampire will affect prices with non-vampire merchants.
$TB_DescNaked	A lack of proper attire will affect prices.
$TB_DescWeapon	Approaching a merchant with a drawn weapon or spell will affect prices.
$TB_DescJobProducers	Local producers include farmers, hunters, and market stall vendors.\nThis setting value indicates the degree to which the buying and selling prices will be decreased\n(i.e. items will cost less to buy, and you'll get less money for items you sell).
$TB_DescJobInns	This setting value indicates the degree to which buying and selling prices are both either increased or decreased.\nPositive values = items cost more to buy, but you'll also get more money for items you sell.\nNegative values = items will cost less to buy, but you'll also get less money for items you sell. 
$TB_DescJobSpecialists	Crafters include blacksmiths, fletchers, apothecaries, jewelers, and tailors.\nThis setting value indicates the degree to which buying and selling prices are both either increased or decreased.\nPositive values = items cost more to buy, but you'll also get more money for items you sell.\nNegative values = items will cost less to buy, but you'll also get less money for items you sell. 
$TB_DescJobSpells	This setting value indicates the degree to which buying and selling prices are both either increased or decreased.\nPositive values = items cost more to buy, but you'll also get more money for items you sell.\nNegative values = items will cost less to buy, but you'll also get less money for items you sell.  
$TB_DescJobGeneral	Buying and selling prices are worse when dealing with general goods traders. These merchants buy low and sell high in order to turn a profit. This setting value indicates the degree to which the buying and selling prices will be worse\n(i.e. items will cost more to buy, and you'll get less money for the items you sell).
$TB_DescJobFence	Buying and selling prices are worse when dealing with a Fence.\nThis setting value indicates the degree to which the buying and selling prices will be worse\n(i.e. items will cost more to buy, and you'll get less money for the items you sell).
$TB_DescVendorRespawn	Choose how many days it will take for merchant inventories to respawn.\nDefault Requiem: 5 Days
$TB_DescVendorRespawnDays	The number of days that it will take for merchant inventories to respawn.\nDefault Requiem: 5 Days
$TB_DescInvestorGold	The amount of gold it will cost to invest with a shopkeeper when you have the Investor perk.\nDefault Requiem: 500
$TB_DescInvestedGoldIncrease	The amount that the merchant's base gold will increase after you haved invested in them.\nDefault Requiem: 1500
$TB_DescInvestorInventory	When you invest in a merchant, it will impact their shop inventory. They may increase their available stock or begin stocking rarer items. Actual effects will vary from merchant to merchant.
$TB_DescMasterTrader	The amount of additional gold that merchants receive if you take the Master Trader perk.\nDefault Requiem: 3000
$TB_DescVariableGold01	Gives select merchants 50 to 2500 more in gold based on lore and location.\nIn particular, merchants in major cities and trading centers will have more gold than those in rural locations.
$TB_DescVariableGold02	Gives select merchants 50 to 4250 more in gold based on lore and location.\nIn particular, merchants in major cities and trading centers will have more gold than those in rural locations.
$TB_DescVariableGold03	Gives select merchants 50 to 6750 more in gold based on lore and location.\nIn particular, merchants in major cities and trading centers will have more gold than those in rural locations.
$TB_DescRandomGold	Adds a random amount of gold on top of the merchant's base gold.  Different merchants will no longer have the exact same amount of gold in their inventories, and the amount of gold they have will change a bit every time their inventory respawns.
$TB_DescApothecaryGold	The base amount of gold that Apothecary vendors will have.\nDefault Requiem: 400
$TB_DescBlacksmithGold	The base amount of gold that Blacksmiths in major cities will have.\nDefault Requiem: 6000
$TB_DescBlacksmithTownGold	The base amount of gold that Blacksmiths in towns will have.\nDefault Requiem: 400
$TB_DescBlacksmithOrcGold	The base amount of gold that Blacksmiths in Orc stongholds will have.\nDefault Requiem: 250
$TB_DescSpellGold	The base amount of gold that Spell merchants will have.\nDefault Requiem: 500
$TB_DescMiscGold	The base amount of gold that General Goods and other miscellaneous vendors will have.\nDefault Requiem: 300
$TB_DescInnGold	The base amount of gold that Innkeepers will have.\nDefault Requiem: 100
$TB_DescStreetGold	The base amount of gold that Market Stall and street vendors will have.\nDefault Requiem: 50
$TB_DescCaravanGold	The base amount of gold that Caravan merchants will have.\nDefault Requiem: 750
$TB_DescFence00Gold	The base amount of gold that Fences will have.\nDefault Requiem: 1000
$TB_DescFence01Gold	The amount of additional gold that Fences receive after stage 1 (increased via the Thieves Guild questline).\nThis amount stacks with previous Fence gold amounts.\nDefault Requiem: 500
$TB_DescFence02Gold	The amount of additional gold that Fences receive after stage 2 (increased via the Thieves Guild questline).\nThis amount stacks with previous Fence gold amounts.\nDefault Requiem: 1000
$TB_DescFence03Gold	The amount of additional gold that Fences receive after stage 3 (increased via the Thieves Guild questline).\nThis amount stacks with previous Fence gold amounts.\nDefault Requiem: 2500
$TB_DescFence04Gold	The amount of additional gold that Fences receive after stage 4 (increased via the Thieves Guild questline).\nThis amount stacks with previous Fence gold amounts.\nDefault Requiem: 5000
$TB_DescDremoraGold	The base amount of gold that the summoned Dremora merchant will have.\nDefault Requiem: 10000
$TB_DescGoldDefault	This will reset changes made to the Vendor Gold lists and set all merchant base gold values back to their Requiem defaults.
